<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computing Science | Visits the Gao Hang&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/computing-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/computing-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computing Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Computing Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/computing-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vechile Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/background/jlu_bach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/background/jlu_bach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;brief-intro&#34;&gt;Brief Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vehicle Engineering major at Jilin University is renowned in the field of automotive education and research.
Researches focus on automotive dynamics and control.
This area delves into the study of vehicle handling stability, ride comfort, and braking performance.
Researchers conduct in-depth investigations into the dynamic characteristics of vehicles under various driving conditions, aiming to develop advanced control strategies and technologies to enhance vehicle safety and maneuverability.
For example, they analyze the effects of suspension systems, tire-road interactions, and steering mechanisms on vehicle dynamics and strive to optimize these components and their control algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mechanical-engineering&#34;&gt;Mechanical Engineering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanical systems are of vital significance in vehicle engineering.
In the design stage, they are used to determine the overall vehicle architecture and conduct component design and selection.
During manufacturing, they enable machining, forming, assembly and commissioning of parts.
In the operation stage, they are responsible for power transmission and conversion.
Overall, mechanical systems permeate every aspect of vehicle engineering, from initial concept to daily use and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controller&#34;&gt;Controller&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controller will be needed to obtain a good performance for vehicles, offering drivers a good driving experience.
Matlab is the basic coding software for design a basic cotroller.
Classic controll methods like PID and statbility criteria like Routh-Hurwitz Criterion is learned.
Laplace Transform methods are used to transform converting a time-domain signal into a frequency-domain signal.
Vehicle specialized softwares, like Prescan, Carsim are used to run the co-simulation on computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;electrical-engineering&#34;&gt;Electrical Engineering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrical Engineering is of utmost significance in the automotive domain.
It is involved in power generation and management via the alternator and battery management systems.
It dictates the design and control of electric motors and associated power electronics in electric and hybrid vehicles.
It shapes vehicle control systems like ECUs and ADAS.
It revolutionizes lighting and signal systems, enhancing visibility and communication.
Also, it drives the development of infotainment and communication systems, enriching the driving experience and laying the foundation for intelligent transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;computing-science&#34;&gt;Computing Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational science, with the help of C++, plays a crucial and multifaceted role in the field of vehicle engineering.
In vehicle dynamics simulation, C++ is used to construct precise models and achieve real-time visualization, facilitating the optimization of handling and stability.
During the development of autonomous driving systems, it undertakes tasks such as sensor data processing, path planning, and decision-making to ensure the safe and intelligent operation of vehicles.
In terms of intelligent transportation system integration, C++ can be employed to develop communication protocols and applications for the Internet of Vehicles, enabling information exchange between vehicles and with infrastructure.
It can also be used for traffic flow optimization, providing a solid technical foundation and a powerful programming tool guarantee for the efficient, intelligent, and safe development of modern vehicle engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;embeded-tech-develop&#34;&gt;Embeded Tech Develop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedded systems are widely and crucially applied in the automotive field.
They are the core of vehicle control systems such as engine control units and transmission control, optimizing engine performance and power transfer.
They also power advanced driver assistance systems like adaptive cruise control and lane departure warning, enhancing driving safety and reducing driver fatigue.
Moreover, they enable infotainment systems, providing multimedia, navigation, and connectivity features, thereby making cars not only a means of transportation but also a hub of entertainment and information, greatly improving the overall driving experience and the intelligence level of vehicles.
During my bachlor range, Aridno UNO and Rawsparrey Pi are used to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thermodynamic&#34;&gt;Thermodynamic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thermodynamics is a branch of physics that studies the relationships between heat, work, energy, and temperature.
Fuel is fired in the combustion, releasing a significant amount of heat energy.
This intense heat causes the gases to expand rapidly, creating high pressure within the combustion chamber.
In this process, gas is generated rapidly from liquid fuel and compressed into different emmision contaminants due to the compression.
Thermodynamic helps understand this process and offers an priciple for optimizing the engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fluid-mechanics&#34;&gt;Fluid Mechanics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Jet flying in the sky, vehicles also concern fluid mechanics when driving in high speed.
The turbulence in fluid mechanics offers an priciple when design the shape of vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
